Register of the David Starr Jordan Papers, 1794-1950
Hoover Institution Archives
David Starr Jordan Papers,
1794-1950
XX240
Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931
88 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 2 card file boxes, 1 oversize folder, 5 scrapbooks, 6 envelopes, memorabilia (42.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, pamphlets, leaflets, clippings, and photographs, relating to pacifism and the movement for world peace, disarmament, international relations, American neutrality in World War I, American foreign and domestic policy, civil liberties in the United States, problems of minorities in the United States, Stanford University, and personal and family matters.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Civil rights--United States.; Disarmament.; Minorities--United States.; Pacifism.; Peace.; World politics.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--20th century.; United States--Neutrality.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; Stanford University.; Universities and colleges--United States.; Education.
Biographical Note
1851 January 19 Born, Gainesville, New York
1869 Entered Cornell University
1872 Bachelor of Arts and Master of Arts, Cornell University
1872-1873 Instructor in botany, Lombard University, Galesburg, Illinois
1873-1874 Principal, Appleton Collegiate Institute, Appleton, Wisconsin
1874-1875 Science teacher, Indianapolis High School, Indianapolis, Indiana
1875 Married Susan Bowen
1875-1879 Professor of natural history, Northwestern Christian University, Irvington, Indiana
1878 Doctor of Philosophy, Northwestern Christian University
1879-1885 Chairman of the Department of Natural Sciences, Indiana University
1885-1891 President, Indiana University
1885 Death of Mrs. Jordan
1887 Married Jessie Knight
1891-1913 President of Stanford University
1913-1916 Chancellor of Stanford University
1916-1931 Chancellor Emeritus of Stanford University
1931 September 19 Died, Stanford, California
Scope and Content
During his lifetime, David Starr Jordan made gifts of his papers to the Hoover Institution (then known as the Hoover War Library). After his death, his widow and friends donated the balance of his papers, including his voluminous correspondence, speeches, writings, notes, and reference materials until, by 1941, the Hoover Institution had custody of almost all of Jordan's papers aside from official university files. In 1945 the papers were divided between the Stanford University Library (these were subsequently included in the Stanford University Archives) and the Hoover Institution, which retained all of the papers dealing with war and peace, most of the papers dealing with international relations, and many papers dealing with U.S. social and political affairs (in areas such as civil liberties, problems of minorities, alien land laws, and higher education).
Series Description
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1794-1931 (Boxes 58-59, 84)
  Jordan family deeds of land purchases in the l8th and 19th centuries, Jordan family geneological research materials, clippings about David Starr Jordan, bookplates, programs, etc., arranged by physical form
- CORRESPONDENCE OF DAVID STARR JORDAN, 1873-1932 (Boxes 1-41, 70-84)
  Correspondence of David Starr Jordan, arranged by name of correspondent. Partial card index to the names of correspondents is available
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1899-1929 (Boxes 42-57)
  Handwritten, typewritten, carbon, and printed copies of speeches, articles, essays, reviews, booklets, leaflets, pamphlets, letters to the editor, public statements, and lectures, arranged in two subseries--one by title and a second for untitled works by subject
- JESSIE KNIGHT JORDAN FILE, 1883-1950 (Boxes 85-88)
  Mrs. Jordan's correspondence, arranged by name of correspondent; her writings, arranged alphabetically by title or subject; miscellaneous subject material, arranged alphabetically by title or subject
- SUBJECT FILE, 1894-1947 (Boxes 58, 60-68)
  Memoranda, reports, notes, collected writings, clippings, leaflets, pamphlets, and other printed material, arranged alphabetically by title or subject
- MISCELLANY, 1910-1929 (Boxes 69, 89-90)
  Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, bound writings, family memorabilia, letterbook, notebook, photograph of faculty of Stanford University, medals, and plaster relief of David Starr Jordan
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1911-1922 (Box 91, map case, on shelf)
  Certificates awarded to David Starr Jordan by the Japanese Government, drawing, paintings, and five large scrapbooks on international relations and war
- AUDIO-VISUAL MATERIAL (Photo file)
  See photo card catalog
Container List
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1794-1931
  - Autobiographical notes (Box 58, Folder 30)
  - Book plates (Folder 31)
  - Clippings
    - 1890 (Folder 32)
    - 1931 (Folder 33)
  - Comments on Jordan's writings (Folder 34)
  - Deeds and records of Jordan family land purchases, 1794-1844 (Folder 35)
  - Magazine articles (Folder 36)
  - Memberships, programs (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Miscellany (Folder 2-3)
  - Newspaper clippings (Folder 4-5)
  - Newspaper extracts (typewritten) (Folder 6)
  - Open Letters to Jordan (published) (Folder 7)
  - Research materials on Jordan family genealogy (Folder 8)
  - Research materials on Jordan family genealogy (Box 84, Folder 22)
  - Subject file
    - Cornell University (Folder 23)
    - Investigation of David Starr Jordan by Naval Intelligence (Folder 24)
    - Peace Plan (Folder 25)
    - Stanford University (Folder 26)
    - Trip to Japan (Folder 27)
  - Writings of family members (Folder 28)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1873-1932
  - Partial card index to correspondence (Box 1)
  - General
    - Undated, fragmentary (Box 2, Folder 1-16)
    - 1873-1877 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1875 (Folder 2)
    - 1881 (Folder 3)
    - 1882 (Folder 4)
    - 1883 (Folder 5)
    - 1884 (Folder 6)
    - 1885, including letters of condolence on death of Jordan's first wife and letters of congratulation on election to presidency of Indiana University (Folder 7)
    - 1886 (Folder 8)
    - 1887, including letters of congratulation on Jordan's second marriage (Folder 9)
    - 1888 (Folder 10)
    - 1889 (Folder 11)
    - 1890 (Folder 12)
    - 1893-1894 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1895 (Folder 2)
    - 1899 (Folder 3)
    - 1900 (Folder 4)
    - 1901 (Folder 5)
    - 1902 (Folder 6)
    - 1903 (Folder 7)
    - 1910 (Folder 8)
    - 1911 (Folder 9)
    - 1913 (Folder 10)
    - 1914 (Folder 11)
    - 1915 (Folder 12-15)
    - 1916 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - 1917 (Folder 5-8)
    - 1917 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - 1918 (Folder 2-8)
    - 1919 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - 1920 (Folder 4-5)
    - 1921 (Folder 6-9)
    - 1921 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1922 (Folder 2-3)
    - 1923 (Folder 4-6)
    - 1924 (Folder 7-8)
    - 1924 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - 1925 (Folder 3-7)
    - 1926 (Folder 8)
    - 1927 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - 1928 (Folder 3-6)
    - 1929 (Folder 7-8)
    - 1930 (Folder 9)
    - 1931 (Folder 10)
    - 1932 (Folder 11)
  - Abbott, Alden H., 1912-1916 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Abbott, J. F., 1916-1923 (Folder 2)
  - Abbott, P. M., 1927 (Folder 3)
  - Adair, James, 1916 (Folder 4)
  - Adams, Bristow, 1915-1928 (Folder 5)
  - Adams, E. D., 1914-1925 (Folder 6)
  - Adams, Edwin F., 1899 (Folder 7)
  - Adams, John, 1912-1923 (Folder 8)
  - Addams, Jane, 1912-1929 (Folder 9)
  - Aiken, Ednah (Mrs. Charles), 1916-1925 (Folder 10)
  - Aked, Charles F., 1911-1915 (Folder 11)
  - Akerson, George, 1929 (Folder 12)
  - Alden, A. H., 1920 (Folder 13)
  - Alderman, E. A., 1912-1915 (Folder 14)
  - Allen, A. W., 1910-1918 (Folder 15)
  - Allen, Ben S., 1919-1923 (Folder 16)
  - Allen, C. G., n.d. (Folder 17)
  - Allen, Devere, 1928 (Folder 18)
  - Allen, James, 1916 (Folder 19)
  - Allen, John Morton, 1923 (Folder 20)
  - Allen, William C., 1911-1924 (Folder 21)
  - Allen, William H., 1914 (Folder 22)
  - Allinson, Brent D., 1918-1919 (Folder 23)
  - Alton, William A., Jr., 1910 (Folder 24)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1914 (Folder 25)
  - American Association for International Conciliation, 1910-1920 (Folder 26)
  - American Association for Labor Legislation, 1914 (Folder 27)
  - American Bankers' Association, 1912 (Folder 28)
  - American Breeders Association, 1913 (Folder 29)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1920-1929 (Folder 30)
  - American Commission on Conditions in Ireland, 1920 (Folder 31)
  - American Committee for Armenian and Syrian Relief, 1922 (Folder 32)
  - American Committee for Relief of Russian Children, 1922 (Folder 33)
  - American Committee for the Celebration of the One Hundredth Anniversary of Peace Among English Speaking Peoples, 1914-1915, 1914 (Folder 34)
  - American Committee for the Outlawry of War, 1922 (Folder 35)
  - American Education, 1914 (Folder 36)
  - American Expeditionary Forces, 1918 (Folder 37)
  - American Friends of German Democracy, 1918 (Folder 38)
  - American Genetic Association, 1914 (Folder 39)
  - American Hebrew, 1922 (Folder 40)
  - American Indian Defense Association, 1923-1924 (Folder 41)
  - American Israelite, 1912 (Folder 42)
  - American Neutral Conference Committee, 1916-1917 (Folder 43)
  - American Order of Clansmen, 1916 (Folder 44)
  - American Peace Award, 1923-1929 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - American Peace Centenary Committee, 1914-1917 (Folder 2)
  - American Peace Society, 1910-1929 (Folder 3)
  - American Peace Society of Japan, 1911-1914 (Folder 4)
  - American Prison Association, 1915 (Folder 5)
  - American Red Cross, 1917-1927 (Folder 6)
  - American Relief Administration, 1922 (Folder 7)
  - American School Peace League, 1911-1914 (Folder 8)
  - American Social Hygiene Association, 1914 (Folder 9)
  - American Society for Cultural Relations with Russia, 1927 (Folder 10)
  - American Society for the Judicial Settlement of International Disputes, 1912 (Folder 11)
  - American Union Against Militarism, 1916-1921 (Folder 12)
  - American Unitarian Association, 1913-1914 (Folder 13)
  - Amnesty Committee, 1919 (Folder 14)
  - Andersen, Hendrik C., 1913-1930 (Folder 15)
  - Anderson, Douglas, 1913 (Folder 16)
  - Anderson, George W., 1910-1922 (Folder 17)
  - Anderson, Melville B., 1913-1918 (Folder 18)
  - Anderson, Robert, 1918 (Folder 19)
  - Andrews, Fannie Fern, 1910-1928 (Folder 20)
  - Angell, James, 1922 (Folder 21)
  - Angell, Norman. See Lane, Ralph
  - Annis, C. H. S., 1923 (Folder 22)
  - Anthony, C. C., 1915 (Folder 23)
  - Anti-Enlistment League, 1916 (Folder 24)
  - Anti-Imperialist League, 1910-1915 (Folder 25)
  - Anti-Saloon League of America, 1914-1921 (Folder 26)
  - Apcar, Diana Agabeg, 1910-1924 (Box 13, Folder 1-5)
  - Appeal to Reason, 1915 (Folder 6)
  - Arctowska, Jane, 1916-1917 (Folder 7)
  - Argonaut, 1911 (Folder 8)
  - Armenian National Union of America, 1920 (Folder 9)
  - Armstrong, Charles, Mrs., 1914 (Folder 10)
  - Armstrong, Lloyd, 1914-1915 (Folder 11)
  - Army and Navy Journal, 1912-1915 (Folder 12)
  - Army and Navy News, 1913-1915 (Folder 13)
  - Army and Navy Register, 1912 (Folder 14)
  - Arnaud, Emile, 1910-1912 (Folder 15)
  - Arnell, C. J., 1923 (Folder 16)
  - Arnold, J. F., 1915 (Folder 17)
  - Association for International Conciliation, 1910 (Folder 18)
  - Atkinson, Henry A., 1920-1931 (Folder 19)
  - Atlantic Monthly, 1913-1921 (Folder 20)
  - Augur, Herbert B., 1915 (Folder 21)
  - Aupperle, D. W., 1917-1918 (Folder 22)
  - Australian Freedom League, 1913-1914 (Folder 23)
  - Australian Friends' Peace Board, 1914 (Folder 24)
  - Australian Peace Alliance, 1916 (Folder 25)
  - Autscback, Carl, 1924 (Folder 26)
  - Awerinzew, S., 1911 (Folder 27)
  - Babbitt, Florence Haynes, 1911 (Folder 28)
  - Babson, Roger W., 1915 (Folder 29)
  - Baggerley, H. L., 1919-1928 (Folder 30)
  - Bailey, Seavey M., 1912 (Folder 31)
  - Bainbridge, Oliver, 1914-1920 (Folder 32)
  - Baker, Harold W. B., 1912 (Folder 33)
  - Baker, James W., 1914 (Folder 34)
  - Baker, Newton D., 1916-1919 (Folder 35)
  - Baker, Ray Stannard, 1920 (Folder 36)
  - Balch, Emily G., 1916-1928 (Folder 37)
  - Baldwin, Roger D., 1917-1929 (Folder 38)
  - Ball, Katherine M., 1914 (Folder 39)
  - Bamber, Ruth C., 1914 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Bannister, L. Ward, 1914-1928 (Folder 2)
  - Barbe, Waitman, 1914 (Folder 3)
  - Barber, Arthur William, 1916 (Folder 4)
  - Bard, Howard D., 1915 (Folder 5)
  - Barnes, Willis L., 1914-1915 (Folder 6)
  - Barr, James, 1913-1915 (Folder 7)
  - Barrett, John, 1913-1915 (Folder 8)
  - Barrow, D. C., 1912 (Folder 9)
  - Barrows, David P., 1913-1922 (Folder 10)
  - Barry, James H., 1912-1924 (Folder 11)
  - Barry, John D., 1914-1924 (Folder 12)
  - Bartels, B. W., 1914-1915 (Folder 13)
  - Barthel, F. K., 1912 (Folder 14)
  - Barthold, Richard, 1913-1916 (Folder 15)
  - Bartlett, C. A. P., 1916 (Folder 16)
  - Bartlett, Lewis, 1920 (Folder 17)
  - Bartnett, W. J., 1923 (Folder 18)
  - Beatson, J. W., 1917-1922 (Folder 19)
  - Beek en Donk, B. de Jong van, 1915-1920 (Folder 20)
  - Behrens, E. C., 1913-1914 (Folder 21)
  - Belfast Evening Telegraph, 1912 (Folder 22)
  - Bell, William M., 1914-1915 (Folder 23)
  - Below, Frank H., Jr., 1920 (Folder 24)
  - Benians, E. A., 1916-1920 (Folder 25)
  - Bennett, G. D., 1915 (Folder 26)
  - Bennett, John E., 1915 (Folder 27)
  - Benson, Allan L., 1915-1918 (Folder 28)
  - Benson, Godfrey Rathbone, 1st Baron of Charnwood, 1918 (Folder 29)
  - Bernays, E. L., 1919 (Folder 30)
  - Bernheimer, Charles L., 1915 (Folder 31)
  - Berthoff, C. F., 1911 (Folder 32)
  - Berwick, Edward, 1911-1930 (Folder 33-34)
  - Beth, (?), 1920 (Folder 35)
  - Beymer, William Gilmore, 1912 (Folder 36)
  - Bigelow, Edward F., 1914 (Folder 37)
  - Bisch, Louis E., 1914 (Folder 38)
  - Blair, Harry M., 1915 (Folder 39)
  - Blake, Kate D., 1914-1915 (Folder 40)
  - Blakeslee, George H., 1915-1919 (Folder 41)
  - Bledsoe, Benjamin F., 1919-1924 (Folder 42)
  - Bliven, Bruce, 1916-1928 (Folder 43)
  - Blumenthal, (?), 1913 (Folder 44)
  - Boardman, Ella C., 1914 (Folder 45)
  - Boardman, Frederick H., 1913 (Folder 46)
  - Boas, Franz, 1922 (Folder 47)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, 1915-1919 (Folder 48)
  - Boggess, F. A., 1915 (Folder 49)
  - Boies, L. G., 1920-1921 (Folder 50)
  - Bok, Edward W., 1923 (Folder 51)
  - Bollack, Leon, 1910-1916 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Bonnell, John K., 1914-1915 (Folder 2)
  - Bonsall, Elizabeth N. (Mrs. Edward H.), 1916 (Folder 3)
  - Book Club of California, 1914 (Folder 4)
  - Booth, Charles F., 1915 (Folder 5)
  - Borah, W. E., 1918-1929 (Folder 6)
  - Bowen, Sarah, 1919-1924 (Folder 7)
  - Bowie, Henry P., 1911-1912 (Folder 8)
  - Bowles, Gilbert, 1912-1928 (Folder 9)
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1913-1918 (Folder 10)
  - Boyle, W. G., 1920 (Folder 11)
  - Brailsford, H. N., 1914 (Folder 12)
  - Brailsford, J. A., 1913 (Folder 13)
  - Brand, Horace L., 1916 (Folder 14)
  - Brandt, Otto S., 1915 (Folder 15)
  - Branner, John Casper, 1910-1918 (Folder 16)
  - Brennan, John, 1899 (Folder 17)
  - Brenneman, D. E., 1915 (Folder 18)
  - Bridges, Russell, 1915 (Folder 19)
  - Brighton and Hove Peace Association, 1913 (Folder 20)
  - Bristol, Susan B., 1917-1924 (Folder 21)
  - British-American Peace Centenary Committee, 1914 (Folder 22)
  - British Columbia Magazine, 1913 (Folder 23)
  - Broda, R., 1916-1929 (Folder 24)
  - Brooks, Raymond C., 1918-1919 (Folder 25)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1913-1923 (Folder 26)
  - Brougham, H. B., 1914 (Folder 27)
  - Brown, Alice M., 1913-1924 (Folder 28-29)
  - Brown, Charles A., 1912 (Folder 30)
  - Brown, Charles R., 1910-1912 (Folder 31)
  - Brown, E. Percival, 1914 (Folder 32)
  - Brown, George, 1910 (Folder 33)
  - Brown, Hillary W., 1914 (Folder 34)
  - Brown, Joseph M., 1912 (Folder 35)
  - Brownell, Atherton, 1913-1916 (Folder 36)
  - Bryan, William Jennings, 1900-1920 (Folder 37)
  - Bryant, Albert G., 1912-1915 (Folder 38)
  - Bryant, Edward A., 1918-1922 (Folder 39)
  - Bryant, Ray W., 1921 (Folder 40)
  - Bryce, James, 1912-1915 (Folder 41)
  - Bryn, M., 1914 (Folder 42)
  - Buchenberger, M. C., 1914-1915 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Bullis, Gilbert P., 1922-1923 (Folder 2)
  - Bunker, Frank F., 1924 (Folder 3)
  - Burbank, Luther, 1915-1925 (Folder 4)
  - Bureau International de Fédérations d'Instituteurs, 1913-1915 (Folder 5)
  - Bureau International de l'Union Postale Universelle, 1911-1914 (Folder 6)
  - Bureau of International Peace, 1912-1914 (Folder 7)
  - Burgess, R. L., 1923-1925 (Folder 8)
  - Burr, George L., 1913 (Folder 9)
  - Burton, Theodore E., 1921-1928 (Folder 10)
  - Bush, Harold M., 1912 (Folder 11)
  - Bushwell, Charles J., 1913 (Folder 12)
  - Butler, Amos W., 1920 (Folder 13)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1910-1930 (Folder 14)
  - Buttlar, Charles, 1911 (Folder 15)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1922-1923 (Folder 16)
  - Byrnes, Thomas P., 1912 (Folder 17)
  - Cabot, Ella Lyman, 1911 (Folder 18)
  - Cahill, J. J., 1913 (Folder 19)
  - Calhoun, Eleanor. See Lazarovich-Hreblianovich
  - California Committee for Relief in Belgium and France, 1918 (Folder 20)
  - California Conference on City Planning, 1914 (Folder 21)
  - California Mooney Defense League, 1919 (Folder 22)
  - California Teachers Association, 1912 (Folder 23)
  - Call, 1915-1921 (Folder 24)
  - Call, Arthur D., 1915-1927 (Folder 25)
  - Camp, Grace Claire, 1914 (Folder 26)
  - Campbell, M. F., 1915 (Folder 27)
  - Canfield, Harry L., 1911 (Folder 28)
  - Cannon, Henry L., 1912-1916 (Folder 29)
  - Cannon, James P., 1927 (Folder 30)
  - Carey, John W., 1914 (Folder 31)
  - Carlisle, C. E., 1915 (Folder 32)
  - Carlsmith, Carl S., 1915-1926 (Folder 33)
  - Carnegie, Andrew, 1914 (Folder 34)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1914-1927 (Folder 35)
  - Carruth, W. H., 1915-1922 (Folder 36)
  - Carson, E. Frank, 1920 (Folder 37)
  - Carter, John N., 1914 (Folder 38)
  - Carter, Mary D., 1914 (Folder 39)
  - Castle, Otis H., 1917 (Folder 40)
  - Caswell, Mary, 1910 (Folder 41)
  - Caton, Charles H., 1922-1928 (Folder 42)
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1928 (Folder 43)
  - Cattell, James McKeen, 1902-1922 (Folder 44)
  - Chamberlain, Henry, 1922-1925 (Folder 45)
  - Chandler, Harry B., 1923-1925 (Folder 46)
  - Channen, Cora H., 1914 (Folder 47)
  - Chester, A. M., 1915 (Folder 48)
  - Chicago Conference on Democracy and Terms of Peace, 1917 (Folder 49)
  - Chicago Tribune, 1915 (Folder 50)
  - Children's Peace Petition Committee, 1914 (Folder 51)
  - China Famine Fund, 1921 (Folder 52)
  - China Famine Relief U.S.A., 1921 (Folder 53)
  - Chinard, G., 1912 (Folder 54)
  - Chinese Chamber of Commerce, San Francisco, 1913 (Folder 55)
  - Chinese Students' Monthly, 1913 (Folder 56)
  - Chittenden, Hiram N., 1911-1914 (Folder 57)
  - Choral Peace Society, 1915 (Folder 58)
  - Christensen, Charles, 1913 (Folder 59)
  - Christensen, Parley Parker, 1924 (Folder 60)
  - Christian, Charles A., 1910 (Folder 61)
  - Christian Herald, 1911 (Folder 62)
  - Church Peace Union, 1915-1916 (Folder 63)
  - Citizens' Committee for Food Shipments, 1916 (Folder 64)
  - Citizens' National Committee, 1914 (Folder 65)
  - Claparède-Spir, Hélène, 1926-1931 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Clapp, Edward B., 1915 (Folder 2)
  - Clark, Ada M., 1915-1920 (Folder 3)
  - Clark, Charles W., 1911 (Folder 4)
  - Clark, George A. (secretary to David Starr Jordan), 1901-1913 (Folder 5)
  - Clark, Grace Julian, 1915 (Folder 6)
  - Clark, John B., 1915 (Folder 7)
  - Clark, John D., 1912 (Folder 8)
  - Clark, Walter, Mrs., 1916 (Folder 9)
  - Cless, Alfred, 1915 (Folder 10)
  - Cleveland Chamber of Commerce, 1913 (Folder 11)
  - Clutts, O. P., 1915 (Folder 12)
  - Cobden Club, 1911-1913 (Folder 13)
  - Cobleigh, Rolfe, 1914 (Folder 14)
  - Cockerell, D. A., Mrs., 1916-1928 (Folder 15)
  - Coffin, Helen A., 1915 (Folder 16)
  - Colcord, Samuel, 1924-1925 (Folder 17)
  - Cole, Frank B., 1912 (Folder 18)
  - Coleman, Anderson, 1914 (Folder 19)
  - Colt, B., Baron, 1921-1924 (Folder 20)
  - Columbian, 1914 (Folder 21)
  - Commission for Relief in Belgium and Northern France, 1917 (Folder 22)
  - Committee for a Cosmopolitan Community House in Sofia, Bulgaria, 1923 (Folder 23)
  - Committee of Forty Eight, 1919-1927 (Folder 24)
  - Committee of 100 Friends of Conscientious Objectors, 1919 (Folder 25)
  - Committee on Cooperation in Latin America, 1921 (Folder 26)
  - Committee on the Limitation of Armament, 1922 (Folder 27)
  - Commons, John R., 1923 (Folder 28)
  - Comstock, Anna, 1895-1929 (Folder 29)
  - Comstock, John H., 1918-1921 (Folder 30)
  - Conklin, Edwin G., 1916 (Folder 31)
  - Conklin, John, 1915 (Folder 32)
  - Conway, Peter V. D., 1912 (Folder 33)
  - Cooley, E. E., 1927-1928 (Folder 34)
  - Cooley, James S., 1915 (Folder 35)
  - Cooley, Stoughton, 1917-1924 (Folder 36)
  - Coolidge, Calvin, 1925-1927 (Folder 37)
  - Cooper, Elwood, 1915 (Folder 38)
  - Cooper, W. A., 1918-1920 (Folder 39)
  - Coover, J. E., n.d. (Folder 40)
  - Copeland, Charles F., 1913-1918 (Folder 41)
  - Copeland, Edward B., 1916 (Folder 42)
  - Copeland, Edwin B., 1915-1918 (Folder 43)
  - Corey, William Alfred, 1913 (Folder 44)
  - Cornell Countryman, 1914 (Folder 45)
  - Cornell University, 1918 (Folder 46)
  - Corwin, R. W., 1914 (Folder 47)
  - Coulter, John M., 1911 (Folder 48)
  - Council of the International Free Trade League, 1909 (Folder 49)
  - Cox, Alvin J., 1918 (Folder 50)
  - Cox, James M., 1920 (Folder 51)
  - Cox-Roosevelt Headquarters, 1920 (Folder 52)
  - Coyle, Albert, 1919-1931 (Folder 53)
  - Craighead, Edward B., 1912 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Crane, Charles R., ca. 1913 (Folder 2)
  - Crawford, Florence Gloria, 1927 (Folder 3)
  - Crooks, J. W., 1913-1914 (Folder 4)
  - Cross, Ira B., 1912 (Folder 5)
  - Crossett, Ella H., 1914 (Folder 6)
  - Crothers, George E., 1923 (Folder 7)
  - Crozier, Bessie Hyde, 1913 (Folder 8)
  - Cumberson, C. E., Mrs., n.d. (Folder 9)
  - Cummings, E. P., 1915 (Folder 10)
  - Cummings, Edward, 1920 (Folder 11)
  - Cunningham, R. J., 1911 (Folder 12)
  - Curran, Garner, 1915 (Folder 13)
  - Curry, Jenny F., 1923 (Folder 14)
  - Curti, Merle Eugene, 1929-1930 (Folder 15)
  - Curtis, J. W., 1911 (Folder 16)
  - Curtis, W., 1911 (Folder 17)
  - Cutler, A. D., 1909 (Folder 18)
  - Cutting, H. C., 1916-1922 (Folder 19)
  - Dabney, Charles W., 1915-1917 (Folder 20)
  - Daily Chronicle, London, 1914 (Folder 21)
  - Daniels, Josephus, 1919 (Folder 22)
  - Danziger, Adolphe, 1918 (Folder 23)
  - Darrow, Clarence, 1931 (Folder 24)
  - Davidson, F. B., Mrs., 1915 (Folder 25)
  - Davignon, H., 1914 (Folder 26)
  - Davis, Charles Henry, 1917 (Folder 27)
  - Davis, Frank P., 1918 (Folder 28)
  - Davis, Horace, 1912 (Folder 29)
  - Davis, Ira G., 1912 (Folder 30)
  - Davis, William Stearns, 1915-1917 (Folder 31)
  - Dawson, W. H., 1918-1919 (Folder 32)
  - Day, Edward, 1915 (Folder 33)
  - Dean, Bashford, 1914 (Folder 34)
  - DeBoer, A., 1913 (Folder 35)
  - Deering, Frank P., 1918-1921 (Folder 36)
  - DeForest, J. H., 1911 (Folder 37)